Van den Haag, Ernest; Papers apap135
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Publications, 1949-2000; 2; 7.49 cubic ft.
  - Numbered, 1950-2000; 2.1; 6.17 cubic ft.
    - 68. "Education as Part of America's Secular Religion - Part I", University Bookman, 1960 Fall (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 82)
    - 69. "Education as Part of America's Secular Religion - Part II". University bookman, 1961 Winter (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 83)
    - 70. "Man's Need to War", Yale Bulletin, 1964 Spring (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 84)
    - 71. "Vietnam: After All Is Said and Done", National Review, 1966 November 29 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 85)
    - 72. "Population and Economic Development", What's New, 1959 Winter (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 86)
    - 73. "Too Few Raisins", Review of "A History of Economic Thought" by Overton H. Taylor, University Bookman, 1959 Winter (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 87)
    - 74. "Introduction" and "Note on Hydrotherapy", in Psychopathia Sexualis by Richard von Krafft-Ebing, NY: Putnam, 1965 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 88)
    - 75. "Sociology", Cowles Comprehensive Encyclopedia, 1964 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 89)
    - 76. "A Head Above the Sand", Review of Thinking About the Unthinkable by Herman Kahn, The Herald Tribune, 1965 January 17 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 90)
    - 77. "Down on Liberals", Review of Up from Liberalism by William F. Buckley, Jr., The New Leader, 1960 April 10 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 91)
    - 78. "The Native of Democracy", Review of Political Power and Personal Freedom by Sidney Hook, New York Times, Undated (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 92)
    - 79. Review of Relativism and the Study of Man, by Schoeck and Wiggins, American Journal of Psychiatry, 1961 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 93)
    - 80. "A Modest Proposal: Abolish Free Colleges", The Sunday Herald Tribune Magazine, 1963 November 17 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 94)
    - 81. Review of "The Family and the Sexual Revolution" ed. by Edwin M. Shur, Behavioral Science Book Service, 1963 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 95)
    - 82. "Kerovac Was Here", Social Problems, 1998 Summer (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 96)
    - 82a. "Kerovac and the Beat: They've Nothing to Say and They Say it Badly", Commentary on "The Dharma Bums" by Jack Kerouac, The Village Voice, 1958 November 05 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 97)
    - 84. "Do Pacifists Harm Peace?" National Review, 1970 December 15 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 98)
    - 85. "Toeing A Familiar Line", Review of One Dimensional Man, by Herbert Marruse, New York Herald Tribune, 1964 April 26 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 99)
    - 86. Letter to the Editor on "The Question of Repression" by Walter Goodman, Commentary, 1970 November (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 100)
    - 87. "Student Seizures: The New Element", Modern Age, 1970 Summer-Fall (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 101)
    - 88. Letter to the Editor on Money in America by Robert Lakachman, Harper's, 1970 October (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 102)
    - 89. "Women, How Equal?" National Review, 1970 September 08 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 103)
    - 90. "Intelligence or Prejudice?" National Review, 1964 December 01 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 104)
    - 91. "Intermarriage and the Race Problem", U.S. News and World Report, 1965 November 18 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 105)
    - 92. "Social Science Testimony in the Desegregation Cases: A Reply to Professor Kenneth Clark", Villanova Law Review, 1960 Fall (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 106)
    - 92b. Published Material on Kenneth Clark, 1955-1968 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 107)
    - 93. "Negroes and Whites: Claims, Rights, and Prospects", Modern Age, 1965 Fall (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 108)
    - 94. "Kill the Pigs and Government", New York Times, 1971 January 21 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 109)
    - 95. Reviews of van Den Haag's "Passion and Social Constraint", 1963-1965 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 110)
    - 96. Letter to the Editor on "Middle Class Violence" by Stark and McEnvoy, Psychology Today, 1971 February (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 111)
    - 97. "There Is More Sex and Less Love", Interview, U.S. News and World Report, 1971 January 26 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 112)
    - 98. "A Dissent from the Consensual Society", Daedlus, 1960 Spring (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 113)
    - 98a. "Shils for Mass Culture", Daedalus, 1959 June (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
    - 99. "Here Comes Da Judge", Review of "Points of Rebellion" by Justice William O. Douglas, Georgia Law Review, and National Review, 1971 May 18 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
    - 100. "On Privacy", In "Privacy" ed. by Pennock and Chapam, Atterton Press, 1971 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
    - 101. "Negative Options: Inherently Fair or Unfair?" Testimony before the Federal Trade Commission, 1970 November 18 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
    - 102. "The Black Studies Smoke Screen", In "The Black Studies Debate" ed. by Jacob V. Gordon, University of Kansas, 1974 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
    - 103. "Essay on Crime: Proposals on Punishment and Prisons", Unpublished, Undated (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
    - 104. "History as Factualized Fiction, "In "Philosophy and History", edited by Sidney Hook, New York Press, 1963 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
    - 105. "Analysis Not Perception, "Review of" The Ethics of Psychoanalysis" by Thomas Szasz, National Review, 1968 November 16 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
    - 106. "On Faith", In "Religious Experience and Faith" ed. by Sidney Hook, New York University Press, 1961 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
    - 107. "Normative and Analytical Welfare Economics", In "Human Values and Economic Policy" ed. by Sidney Hook, New York University Press, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
    - 108. "Competition in Conflict", In "The Fabric of Society", Undated (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
    - 109. "Mass Media and the Intellectual", Columbia Univ. Seminar on Public Communications, 1961 November 17 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
    - 111. "Featherbedding", L'informateur, 1965 December 15 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
    - 113. Review of "On the Contrary" by Mary McCarthy, National Review, Undated (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
    - 120. "On Torture", Review of "The Wretched of the Earth" by Frantz Fanon, Modern Age, 1966 Spring (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
    - 121. Clinical Detachment and "Passionate Intensity", The Journal of Group Psychoanalysis and Process, 1969 Winter-1970 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
    - 122. "Introduction", (Secondary School Textbooks), University Bookman, Fall and, 1966 Summer (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
    - 123. "On Diagnosed Mental Illness and Social Class (I), "American Sociological Review, 1966 August (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
    - 125. Reviews of "Education as an Industry" by Ernest van den Haag, NY: Kelly and Millman, 1956 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
    - 124. "Buckley and Vidal", Letter to the Editor on William F. Buckley, Jr. and Gore Vidal, Encounter, 1970 March (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
    - 126. "Psychoanalysis and the Social Sciences", In "Psychoanalysis and the Social Sciences" ed. by H.R Rvitenbeck, NY: E.P. Dutton, 1962 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
    - 127. "Deterrence and the Death Penalty", Rejoinder on "The Death Penalty as a Deterrent" by Hugo Adam Bedau, Ethics, 1970 October (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
    - 128. "Government, Conscience, and Disobedience", In "Sidney Hook and the Contemporary World" edited by Paul Kurtz, John Day Company, 1968 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
    - 129. Letter to the Editor on "The Great Society, 1967" by Robert Lekachman, Commentary, Undated (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
    - 130. Letter to the Editor on "Our Prisons are Criminal" by Bruce Jackson, New York Times Magazine, 1968 October 20 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 25)
    - 131. Reply to "Ending the Welfare Mess" Letter by Richard Rene, National Review, 1969 January 28 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 26)
    - 132. "Let's Drop Prejudice Against Prejudice", Unpublished, Undated (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 27)
    - 133. "One Man's Mead, Another Man's Poison", Review of "Culture and Commitment" by Dr. Margaret Mead, The Atlantic, 1970 June (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 28)
    - 134. "How To Keep the Peace", Journal of Atlantic Science, Undated (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 29)
    - 135. "A Rationing Rate Structure", Journal of Land and Public Utility Economics, 1943 May (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 30)
    - 136. Civil Disobedience and the Law "Rutgers Law Review", 1966 Fall (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 31)
    - 136a. "Civil Disobedience", Manuscript for "Political Violence and Civil Disobedience" In Britannica Encyclopedia, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 32)
    - 137. "Psychoanalysis and Fantasy", National Review, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 33)
    - 138. Quoted in "Mothers and Sons: The Ultimate Hang Up", Cosmopolitan, 1967 May (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 34)
    - 139. "The Case For Pornography Is The Case For Censorship and Vice Versa", Esquire, 1967 May (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 35)
    - 140. "The Popularity of Art", The Critic or the Visual Arts, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 36)
    - 141. "The Negative Role of Religion In a Pluralistic Society", Lecture Given at University of Notre Dame, Undated (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 37)
    - 142. "Introduction" (College Textbooks of American History and Sociology), University Bookman, 1967 Fall (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 38)
    - 142a. "Conclusion", (On College Textbooks) edited by Haag, University Bookman, 1968 Winter (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 39)
    - 143. "Is Pornography a Cause of Crime?" Encounter, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 40)
    - 143a. "Pornographers and Censors", Reply to J.W. Lambert on Pornography Encounter, 1968 July (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 41)
    - 144. "Conspicuous Consumption of Self", National Review, 1968 April 11 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 42)
    - 145. "How to Prevent Civil Disorders", National Review, 1968 March 26 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 43)
    - 146. "A Fitting Farewell", Review of "Progress & Revolution" by Robert Waelder Psychiatry and Social Science Review, 1968 March (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 44)
    - 147. Reviews of "The Jewish Mystique" by Ernest van den Haag, Stein and Day, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 45)
    - 147b. "Forbidden Fruit", Excerpt from "The Jewish Mystique", Cosmopolitan, 1970 April (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 46)
    - 148. "War, Peace and the Grand Illusion", Review of "Sanity and Survival", by Jerome Frank, Chicago Tribune Book World, 1968 February 18 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 47)
    - 149. "Money to Burn", (Riot Control), National Review, 1968 July (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 48)
    - 150. "Booklearning and Barricades", The Washington Post, Book World, 1968 August 04 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 49)
    - 151. "On Deterrence and The Death Penalty", Ethics, 1968 July (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 50)
    - 151a. "On Deterrence and The Death Penalty", Journal of Criminology Law, Criminology and Police Science, 1969 June (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 51)
    - 152. "Ending the Welfare Mess", National Review, 1968 December 17 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 52)
    - 152a. "Poverty and Welfare" Lecture at the Intercollegiate Studies Institute, Philadelphia, PA, Undated (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 53)
    - 153. "Poverty and Welfare: A Liberal-Conservative Dialogue", National Review, 1968 November (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 54)
    - 154. "Passionate Simplemindedness", Letter to the Editor on "Who Shall Prepare Himself for Battle?" by Thomas Ford Hoult, The American Sociologist, 1968 August (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 55)
    - 155. "Intimidation and Terror", (The Black Panthers), unpublished, Undated (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 56)
    - 156. A reply to "Challenge to the Court" by I.A. Newby, Louisiana State University Press, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 57)
    - 157. Review of "The Year 2000", by Herman Kahn, The American Journal of Sociology, 1968 September (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 58)
    - 158. "Literature in the Dock", Review of "The End of Obscenity" by Charles Rembar, Book World, 1968 July (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 59)
    - 159. Response to "Classified Military Research and The University", by Anatol Raport, The Humanist, 1969 February (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 60)
    - 160. Letter to the Editor on "Elegant Tombstones", by C.B. MacPherson, Dissent, 1969 May (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 61)
    - 161. "In Defense of Punishment", Fortune, and Human Events, 1968 December 31; 1968 December (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 62)
    - 162. "Why Sex Education", National Review, and Current, 1969 September 23; 1969 November (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 63)
    - 163. "The Court and Welfare", National Review, 1969 August (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 64)
    - 164. "Conversations on the New Eroticism", Interview, Time, 1969 July 11 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 65)
    - 165. "The University As a Progressive Kindergarten", The Intercollegiate Review, 1969 Spring (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 66)
    - 166. "John Calder's Illusions", Encounter, 1970 August (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 67)
    - 167. "Blackness and Competence", Letter to the Editor, The American Sociologist, 1969 February (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 68)
    - 168. "Literature or License", undated, and "The American Culture Explosion: Fact or Fiction, Appearances" on The Open Mind, WNBC Television, 1965 January 24 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 69)
    - 168a. "Human Rights Issues Related to the Causes and Justifications for Student Unrest", Appearance on "Right Now", WOR-TV, New York, 1969 May 25 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 70)
    - 168b. "Should the Legislative Recommendations of the Pornography Commission be Adopted?" Appearance on The Advocates, KCET, Los Angeles, 1970 November 17 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 71)
    - 169. Letter to the Editor on Bill Moyers, The Atlantic, 1969 May (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 72)
    - 170. "Poor Statistics", Letter to the Editor on "The Big Money" by John Thompson, Commentary, 1969 May (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 73)
    - 171. Letter to the Editor on "The American Underclass", by Lee Rainwater, Trans-action, 1969 April (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 74)
    - 172. "Jensen's Article is a Good Beginning", Harvard Educational Review, "More on Jensen's Genes", Transaction, and "Addendum to Jensen", American Psychologist, 1969 Summer; 1969 October; 1969 November (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 75)
    - 172a. Arthur Jensen Files, 1969-1973 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 76)
    - 173. "The Student Rebels", The New School Bulletin, 1969 October (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 77)
    - 174. "Sociology and Religion", Address Delivered at a Jewish Theological Seminary Faculty Seminar, 1965 February 08 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 78)
    - 175. "The Honorable Alternative: Nixon on November 3", National Review, 1970 January (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 79)
    - 176. "What's Missing in Nixon's Welfare Program?" National Review, 1970 January 27 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 80)
    - 177. "The Campus and The Law", National Review, 1969 December 02 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 81)
    - 178. Review of "Epistle to the Babylonians", by Charles Fontenay, Social Research, 1971 Spring (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 82)
    - 180. "Civil Liberties and War", American Civil Liberties Union Biennial Conference, 1966 June (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
    - 181. "Appetite for Salvation", Review of "The Mass Psychology of Fascism" by Wilhelm Reich, The New Leader, 1971 February 08 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
    - 182. "Religion in America" Modern Age, 1971 Summer (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
    - 183. "Causes and Prevention of Ramsey Clark", Review of "Crime in America Observation on It's Nature, Causes, Prevention, and Control" by Ramsey Clark, National Review, 1971 March 31 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
    - 186. "To Break Mid-east Logjam", New York Times, 1971 April 18 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
    - 187. "Research and A Report", Letter to the Editor On Presidential Commission on Obscenity, Commentary, 1971 July (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
    - 188. "Art and the Mass Audience", Art in America, 1971 July-1971 August (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
    - 189. "Labor and Economics", Letter to the Editor on Reinstitution of Investment Credit and Work Rules or Practices, New York Times, 1971 August 13 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
    - 190. "The Military and Morality", New York Times, 1971 August 13 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
    - 191. "Debate: Is School an Appropriate Place for Sex Education?" Sexual Behavior, 1971 August (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
    - 192. "Power to the Students", Letter to the Editor on "Give Power to the Students", National Review, 1971 May 18 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
    - 193. "To Southeast Asia with Reservations", National Review, 1971 September 24 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
    - 194. Letter from Richard Nixon, Appearance on the Dick Cavett Show, 1971 August 02 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
    - 195. "U.S. Crimes in Vietnam", National Review, 1971 October 22 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
    - 196. "When Is A Crime A War Crime?" National Review, 1971 November 11 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
    - 197. "Race Then and Now", Review of "American Statesmen on Slavery and the Negro" by Nathaniel Weyl and William Marina, National Review, 1971 November 11 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
    - 198. "Notes on Attica", Eastern Group Psychotherapy Society Newsletter, 1971 December (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
    - 199. "Brilliant Shafts and Coherent Whole", Review of "Politics and Passion by S.M. Lipset, National Review, 1972 February 04 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
    - 200. "Civil Disobedience", National Review, and Quadrant, 1972 January 21; 1972 March-April (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
    - 201. Interview in Histoire d'O Calcutta by Andre Balland, Undated (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
    - 203. "Through the Rabbit Hole", National Review, 1969 November (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
    - 204. "Moral Rights and the Law, Intercollegiate Review, 1972 Winter-Spring (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
    - 206. Testimony on the Death Penalty Before the Judiciary Committee, March 15, 1972, and Excerpts in Congressional Digest, 1973 January (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
    - 207. Letter to the Editor on William Shannon's Day Care Center Article, Sunday Times Magazine, 1972 May 21 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
    - 208. Calamitous Cardinal", Review of "Three Popes and the Cardinal" by Malachi Martin, National Review, 1972 May 26 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 25)
    - 209. Letter to the Editor on "Ethics of Addiction" by Thomas Szasz, Harpers, 1972 June (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 26)
    - 210. "Of Men and Bees", Review of "The Insect Societies" by Edward O. Wilson, National Review, 1972 June 23 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 27)
    - 211. "Should Congress Ban Private Ownership of Handguns?" Appearance on The Advocates, PBS Broadcasting, KCET, Los Angeles, 1971 November 16 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 28)
    - 212. Reply to Richard Archer's Review of "Political Violence and Civil Disobedience", Quadrant, 1972 September-1972 October (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 29)
    - 213. "Sex Education", Appearance on Firing Line, PBS, Southern Educational Communications Association, New York City, 1972 October 15 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 30)
    - 214. "On the Nature Causes and Effects of Political Violence", Catholic University Law School, 1971 October (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 31)
    - 215. "The Munich Murders: Will Violence Rule the World?" To the Point, 1972 September 09 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 32)
    - 216. Review of "On Record: Files and Dossiers in America Life" edited by Stanton Wheeler, American Journal of Sociology, 1972 November (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 33)
    - 217. "The Tortured Search for the Cause of Inequality", National Review, 1973 February 16 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 34)
    - 218. Review of "The Primal Revolution" by Arthur Janov, The New Leader, 1972 December 25 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 35)
    - 219. Reviews of Political Violence and Civil Disobedience, Harper and Row, 1973 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 36)
    - 219a/b. Reply to D.A. Zoll, University Bookman, Summer 1973, and Reply to Robert Hall, Humanist, January/February, 1974 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 37)
    - 219c. Reply to Saul Brenner Contemporary Sociology, 1975 March (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 38)
    - 219d. Reply to Jeffrey Murphy American Political Science Review, 1975 June; 1976 June (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 39)
    - 221. "Everybody Above Average", For University Centers for Rational Alternatives, Undated (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 40)
    - 221a. "Everybody Above Average", The Alternatives, 1973 December (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 41)
    - 222. "Moral Rights and the Law: A Response to Dworkin", The Intercollegiate Review (Winter/Spring 1972), and Reply to Machan (Winter 1972-1973) (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 42)
    - 223. "Is it True that Violence Breeds Violence?" The International Journal of Group Tensions, Vol. 3, Nos. 1-2, 1973 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 43)
    - 224. Comment on Arthur Bremer's Diary, Harper's, 1973 February (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 44)
    - 225. Skeptical Comments on Bisexuality", The Humanist, 1973 July-1973 August (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 45)
    - 227. "Notes on Group and Ethnic Relationships", Plural Societies, 1973 Fall (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 46)
    - 228. Reply to A.P. Lerner's letter on "The Tortured Search for the Causes of Inequality", National Review, 1973 March 16 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 47)
    - 229. "Contemporary Students and Universities", In Private Higher Education: The Job Ahead, reprint of 1972 Annual meeting, Scottsdale, Arizona, 1973 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 48)
    - 230. Letter to the Editor on "Conservatives and Original Sin" by Andrew Hacker, Sunday New York Times Magazine, 1973 April 01 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 49)
    - 231. "Educational Inflation", Imprimis, and The University Bookman, 1973 August; 1975 Spring (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 50)
    - 231a. "Education Inflation", Revised and reprinted in The University Bookman, 1975 Spring (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 51)
    - 232. Review of "Karl Marx on Revolution: Karl Marx Library Vol. I", and "Karl Marx on America and the Civil War: Karl Marx Library, Vol. II", edited by Saul Radover, National Review, 1973 June 22 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 52)
    - 233. Review of "The Ideological Imagination" by Louis J. Halle, Contemporary Sociology, 1973 July (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 53)
    - 234. Review of "Sociology, Morals and Mystery" by Sir Roy Harrod, Contemporary Sociology, 1973 November (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 54)
    - 235. Discussion Panel: "New Sexual Life Styles", Playboy, 1973 September (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 55)
    - 236. "Meat Axe as Criticism", Review of "Sociology as Sorcery" by Stanislav Andreski, National Review, 1974 February 01 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 56)
    - 237. Reviews of "The Balancing Act", 1975 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 57)